Alan Sanderson

21 Havisham Close, Birchwood, Warrington WA3 7NB Mobile: 07982 138 896

Email: ajsandyman@gmail.com

Professional Profile

Highly organized, experienced IT management professional skilled at planning, research and problem solving. Attentive eye to detail, with ability to make key decisions under pressure. Experienced in time management and enjoys working both in a team setting, as well as independently.

Objective

Seeking a position that is able to utilize my management and professional skills, and allows me to contribute to the overall success of the business. I would also be open to alternative roles.

Career Summary

Oct.2018-To Date 2nd Line Support Engineer, Fairhome Group PLC - (Permanent)

My key responsibilities include;

- Technical resolution of incidents at 1st and 2nd line.
- To act as the single point of contact for all IT related service requests.
- Logging calls with 3rd parties and incident management.
- Timely progression of all incidents and requests to ensure SLA's are met.
- Tracking of all incidents and escalation where appropriate and closure of incidents on confirmation from the customer of satisfactory resolution.
- Installation and configuration of IT equipment.
- User account administration.
- PC & Laptop builds.

Apr.2018-Sep.2018 IT Support Administrator, Chapel Outsourcing Ltd - (Permanent)

- The main duties of this role is to assist with the day-to-day functions of the computer systems throughout the business and to contribute to the overall efficiency of the local area network by providing technical support to all departments and users across two office locations.
- Manage Exchange users via the Exchange Admin Centre console.
- Process new starters and leavers for access to corporate systems.
- Administering user accounts, software installations & configurations, system and application troubleshooting and general PC/Network Support.
- Setup and configure new Desktops/Laptops.
- Make changes to the Fortigate 100E firewall to allow for external company access to internal databases and SFTP folder access.
- Assist with the Dialler (Noble, Maestro, and Harmony) desk phone routing, deal with issues, update correct skill set and dialling groups.
- Updates to the Polycom desk phones and make necessary changes to IP Cortex when setting up new users.
- Update local WiFi access for new users and setup temporary access for visitors.
- Manage the company Email and Spam filter Mimecast portal for email security.
- Monitor server backup routines
- Perform restores from backup using Veeam backup software
- Monitor the VMWare virtual infrastructure.
- Adding email accounts to user mobile phones.
- Support and update local switches when moving network attached equipment between different subnets/VLAN's.
- Assist with Asset Control.
- Manage Sophos Antivirus
- Manage issues with company Copiers/Printers and log faults and maintenance requests with Xerox.

•

Dec.2017-Feb.2018 Application Support Analyst, Home Instead Senior Care UK Ltd.-(Permanent)

- My primary role is to support the franchise network in the use of the business applications that are provided to them. This includes a range of software specific to the industry, including the core care management system (PeoplePlanner), as well as complimentary systems which sit around this for call monitoring, data capture and recruitment.
- My role also includes email system administration on Office 365, as well as a managed IMAP platform and Hosted Exchange.
- In addition to the above duties, which revolve around the support of the network of 190 offices, I am also responsible for the internal support of the National Office and its 50 users. This only forms a small part of this role; however it is an essential part to keep the National Office running.

Nov.2001-Nov.2017 ICT Manager, Cruden Construction, Ltd. – (Permanent)

- Provided maximum availability for computer systems throughout the company's network infrastructure, which consists of 2 office buildings, six depots and an average of 14 construction sites.
- Managing day-to-day IT requirements of the company to its users such as user management, trouble shooting, help and advice, and maintenance of desktop applications.
- Provision of Desktop Operating System support / troubleshooting to all users of Windows 7 / 10 and earlier environments.
- Overseeing the Local and Wide Area Networks and IT Security & Telecommunications for the company.
- Managing one ICT Support Analyst and support provision for 250+ users.
- Improving the IT infrastructure and implementing new technologies, hardware and software installations for the company.
- Providing the maintenance and repair of systems and software as needed.
- Performing routine audits of systems and software.
- Managing the IT budget and all financial administration of hardware, software, systems and services, management of server software and associated backup routines.
- Maintaining BS ISO IEC 27001: 2005 & Business Continuity systems and procedures.
- Managing the provision of internet and telecommunications facilities to support a large office relocation.

2000-2001 PC & Network Support, Sutton & Son (St. Helen's) Ltd. – (Contract)

- Providing 2nd and 3rd Line Support to approximately 250 users.
- Contributing to the provision of telephone remote support to both UK users and abroad.
- Upgrading desktop PC's, laptops and printers.
- Providing Unix, data and voice network and Cab (truck) phone fault diagnosis support.
- Working as part of a team to ensure quality service provision.

Feb. 2000-Dec. 2000 PC & Network Support, Heinz Frozen & Chilled Foods, Grimsby – (Contract)

- Providing 1st & 2nd line support for United Biscuits legacy IT infrastructure, including Netware 4.11 administration.
- Building & configuring PC workstations.
- Installing printers and modems.
- Providing telephone support to a number of remote sites around the UK.
- Rolling out new PC systems as part of a migration from older United Biscuits systems to a standard Heinz Windows NT 4.0 desktop.
- Performing integration testing of legacy UB software on the new NT platform.

1999-2000 PC & NETWORK SUPPORT, Royal Doulton Ltd., Stoke-on-Trent – (Contract)

- Working within the IT Helpdesk, providing PC and network support for 500 users on six sites based around the Stoke-on-Trent area.
- Providing network & user administration of Netware 4.11 servers and Windows 95/NT workstations.
- Organizing and running an IT Support training course for other members of the department.
- Checking & upgrading PC's for Y2K compliance.
- Advising management team on strategies for improving the support environment.

March 1999- August 1999 TECHNICAL SUPPORT ANALYST, United Biscuits Ltd. (UK) – (Contract)

- Providing 1st and 2nd Line PC and network support for 300+ users, based at their sites in Grimsby and Annan.
- Building and configuring Y2K compliant PC's using Windows 95 and 'Client 2000' software.
- Providing network support and administration, including Netware 4.11 NAL user admin.
- Installing and configuring all LAN hardware.

1997-1999 TECHNICAL SUPPORT ANALYST, The Law Society, Learnington Spa – (Contract)

- Providing 1st and 2nd Line Support to a community of 300+ Windows 95 and NT users.
- Migrating all PC users from Windows 3.1/Lotus.
- Administering NT server, user account management, troubleshooting software and hardware issues.
- Maintaining the LAN infrastructure.

March 1997 – August 1997 SERVICE DELIVERY & SUPPORT ANALYST, Transco (British Gas), Birmingham – (Contract)

- Administering user accounts, software installations & configurations, system and application troubleshooting and general Novell support.
- Managing review of IT department procedures for receiving and handling user requests.
- Liaising with members of the Helpdesk team and senior management.

NETWORK ADMINISTRATOR, British Rail Business Systems Computing, Nottingham – (Permanent)

- Supervising and administering of a Novell Local Area Network, consisting of 350 users and over 20 Netware file servers (v2.15 v3.12).
- Assuring the LAN was integrating with an SNA network to allow users access to the company's IBM mainframes and troubleshooting as necessary.

1991-1993

ASSISTANT OPERATIONS CONTROLLER, British Rail Business Systems Computing, Nottingham - (Permanent)

- Providing assistance with the implementation and production of computer systems.
- Liaising with system users for problem determination and the provision of suitable data security.
- Assisting with the control and maintenance of bureau disk storage and the provision of on-line access facilities.

1984-1991

SENIOR COMPUTER OPERATOR, British Rail Business Systems Computing, Nottingham – (Permanent)

• Operating ICL 2982 and IBM 3090 mainframe systems.

Education and Oualifications

NCFE LEVEL 2 Certificate In Equality And Diversity 2017

Indirect Tax, 2017 **AAT Level 3 (AQ2013) AAT Level 3 (AQ2013)** Cost and Revenues, 2017

Prepare Final Accounts for Sole Traders and Partnerships, 2017 **AAT Level 3 (AQ2013)**

AAT Level 3 (AQ2013) Accounts Preparation, 2017 Certificate in Accounting, 2016 **AAT Level 2 (AQ2013)**

Microsoft Certified Professional: NT Server v4.0, 2000

Microsoft Certified Professional: NT Server v4.0 Enterprise, 2000 **Microsoft Certified Professional:** NT Workstation v4.0, 1999

'Network Essentials – Exam 70-058,'1999 **Microsoft:**

BTEC: National Certificate in Computer Studies, Including: Pascal &

> Cobol Programming, Computer Systems, Information Systems. Small Business Systems, Practice & Concepts, Quantitative Methods, Accounting & Auditing, Communication, 1996

Mathematics, 1990 GCSE:

City & Guilds: Non-vocational Assignment in Computer Literacy, 1985 5 CSEs:

Studies Include: Engineering Science, Electronics,

English, Design and Art

Key I.T. Skills

- ➤ PC Operating Systems XP/7/10
- MS Office 2003/2007/2010/2013/2016
- \triangleright Office 365
- Microsoft Word
- PowerPoint
- Citrix Access Gateway
- HP Core 2 Duo Workstations
- Sonicwall NSA 2400/TZ170 Firewalls
- Arcserve 2000 v7
- Smartsuite v4.0 & 97,
- Lotus Notes,
- SMS 2.0
- ➤ Dell Poweredge 6300/4200 servers
- ➤ Groupwise v4.0 & v5.0
- Microsoft Hyper-V
- Storagecraft ShadowProtect VSS
- Veeam Backup & Replication
- ➤ FortiGate 100E
- Sophos Anti-Virus
- Mimecast Email Security
- SmoothWall Web Filtering
- Exclaimer Signature Manager
- Sage Payroll / 200
- ManageEngine ServiceDesk Plus

- Microsoft Windows Server 2003
- WMware 3.5/6.5, SQL 2000
- Backup Exec 10d
- Snapguard Web Filtering
- ➤ HP Proliant DL380 G2 Servers
- ➤ Dell Power Connect 5324 Gigabit Switches
- Unix AIX v4.0
- Compaq Proliant ML 370/HP Netserver LC3 server
- Pentium-II/III workstations
- Novell Netware 4.11
- Dell, Fujitsu & Compaq PC's
- ➤ Windows Server 2008/12/16 Active Directory
- ➤ Dell Poweredge T610 Quad-Core Xeon Servers
- ➤ HP DL360 Host
- ➤ HP StorageWorks P2000
- ➤ HP StorageWorks 2040
- Avaya 4850GTS-PWR+ Switch
- Avaya 7024XLS Switch
- Avaya 5632FD Switch
- Polycom VVX 300 VOIP Phones
- > IPCortex
- Maestro Noble Systems

Personal Details

Interests: Reading, Health & Fitness, Fell Walking, Cinema

Other: Driver; full UK license

References

Fairhome Group Plc - Mark Latham IT Service Desk Manager (mlatham@fairhomegroup.co.uk)

Chapel Outsourcing Ltd

Reference Contact: Sue Love – Associate Director and Head of HR

(sue.love@firsttargetrecoveries.co.uk)

Home Instead Senior Care UK Ltd

Reference Contact: Dave Butler - IT Support (david.butler@homeinstead.co.uk)

Cruden Contruction Ltd

Reference Contact: Michelle Swarbrick – HR Manager (<u>mswarbrick@crudengroup.co.uk</u>)